ABDUL REHMAN SOHAIL

 $+923333430018 \diamond Gulberg III, Lahore$

♦ abdulrehmansohail786@gmail.com ♦ linkedin.com/in/abdulrehmans0hai1

OBJECTIVE

Experienced Backend Developer with 4 years of expertise in Python, Django, and Django Rest Framework. I am self-motivated and continuously seek to expand my software engineering skills. I aspire to progress to the role of Senior Software Engineer. My aim to contribute to web development, AI, and machine learning projects and eager to apply my knowledge and experience in a Senior Software Developer role.

EDUCATION

BS Information Technology - The Islamia University of Bahawalpur

3.32/4.0

Feb 2018 - Feb 2022

SKILLS

Programming Languages Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Backend Frameworks Django, Django Rest Framework(DRF), FastAPI

Databases PostgreSQL, SQLite, Redis

ToolsCelery, CronJobVersion ControlGit, BitBucketCloudDocker, AWS

Soft Skills Team Player, Communication, Adaptable

EXPERIENCE

Backend Engineer
Beyond Eris Solutions

Nov 2022 - Present

Lahore

- At Beyond Eris Solutions, I am responsible for developing and maintaing new and existing products using Python, Django and Django Rest Framework (DRF) utilizing Agile software development methodologies.
- Collaborated with frontend-developers to develop the required APIs.
- Introduced and promoted best practices for code quality, performance, and security across the development team.
- As a senior developer I have been part of client meetings and gathered requirements and converted them into a running system.
- Actively participated in a project management role, knowledge-sharing sessions, and staying updated with the latest industry trends and technologies.
- Optimized the performance of the existing system which resulted in significant reduction in API response time.
- Worked closely with DevOps Engineer to ensure the availability of the system.

Python Django Developer

Feb 2021 - Oct 2022

Bahawalpur

Enigmatix Pvt. Ltd.

- My responsibilities at Enigmatix Pvt. Ltd. included the development of new and existing products using Agile software development methodologies.
- I am part of a team working on multiple products developed in Django, Django Rest Framework, React Native and React Js.
- Managed projects and collaborated effectively using Agile methodologies, ensuring efficient project execution and timely deliveries.
- Collaborated with frontend-developers to develop the required APIs.
- Conducted and participated in Agile Scrum ceremonies, contributing to sprint planning, stand-ups, and retrospectives.

PROJECTS

Luxury Explorers ERP - Beyond Eris Solutions

Implemented a customized Luxury Explorers ERP system for UAE-based businesses, enhancing operational efficiency with modules for Accounting, Operations, HR, Leaves, Payroll, and System Permissions. Utilized Python, Django Rest Framework, and agile methodology to develop REST APIs for seamless integration. Streamlined leaves management and payroll processes, ensuring compliance with UAE regulations. Automated data analysis for financial reporting, reducing manual errors by 20 percent. The ERP system effectively maintained regulatory standards and optimized overall processes.

Washland - Beyond Eris Solutions

Developed customized financial reports for the executive team, enabling data-driven decision-making. Utilized Python, Django, and DRF to design scalable API solutions for accounting processes and implemented an automated report generation system, increasing efficiency in financial data analysis. Resolved system bottlenecks, reducing website load times. Implemented a role-based permissions management system using Python and Django, enhancing security and efficiency.

Etail - Beyond Eris Solutions

I developed customized financial reports for the executive team, enhancing data-driven decision-making, and implemented an automated report generation system that increased efficiency. I also utilized Python, Django, and DRF to design scalable API solutions for accounting processes and implemented a role-based permissions management system, boosting security. Additionally, I resolved system bottlenecks, reducing website load times.

Booster Tech - Beyond Eris Solutions

Implemented Booster Tech's accounting solution for a Spain-based business, including the successful deployment of Version 2 and seamless Spanish localization. Developed intricate reporting mechanisms to enhance user experience and operational transparency. Identified areas for optimization and implemented Django Rest Framework-specific performance enhancements.

Growtal - Enigmatix

Developed and managed Growtal, a freelance marketplace platform. Implemented Django Rest Framework, enhancing API response time and integrated email and social authentication. Established automated email verification with SendGrid and phone verification with Twilio, and streamlined user role assignment, reducing manual workload

Passages - Enigmatix

Developed and launched Passages, a mobile application for Android and iOS that enables memory sharing among users. Implemented user-friendly features like photo/video uploads, comments, and notifications to boost engagement. Utilized Python, Django Rest Framework, PostgreSQL, and OAuth for backend efficiency. Integrated SendGrid for email verification and Stripe for seamless payment processing. Additionally, implemented event creation, member management, and event invitation features.

Al Hilal Academy - Enigmatix

I conducted client meetings and gathered requirements for new modules, managed player registrations and team assignments, and handled membership and inventory management. I generated invoices and player performance reports, optimized the codebase to boost system performance and utilized backend technologies including Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, PostgreSQL, and Cron Jobs. Additionally, I customized the Django Admin Panel for improved data management.

LEADERSHIP

- I have lead of team of 3 Back-end Developers and mentor them.
- I have trained 2 junior Python Developers.

LANGUAGES

- English
- Urdu